<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Pranav Rayudu's Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Pranav Rayudu's blog]]></description><link>https://pranavrayudu.github.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 04:52:57 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[CS373 Fall 2021: Taraka Pranav Rayudu]]></title><description><![CDATA[What did you do this past week? This past week, I managed to cook all the new recipes I learnt from my mother. Most of those are curries and…]]></description><link>https://pranavrayudu.github.io/cs373-fall21-post-2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://pranavrayudu.github.io/cs373-fall21-post-2/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 630px; &quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/db8dd83596b9c3016ab8dbe7347cb64b/377b2/potrait.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 100%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAUABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFwABAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAMCBP/EABcBAQADAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAIAAQP/2gAMAwEAAhADEAAAAdSpIurBGHKaG4uf/8QAGhAAAwEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAERAhIDIv/aAAgBAQABBQJsfxssPTc0Vl6fTP/EABYRAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEQIf/aAAgBAwEBPwEMhP/EABgRAAMBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABMRAR/9oACAECAQE/AXcdOH//xAAdEAACAgEFAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAARARIQMSMVFh/9oACAEBAAY/AuvRVqb05SxF2ZOT/8QAHBAAAwADAAMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAERIVFhEHGh/9oACAEBAAE/IXYSeTnAvUhaKK1ifs3BiwvG4qE1fgiP/9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABD74ED/xAAXEQEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABABEQ/9oACAEDAQE/EAU8Tjbf/8QAFxEBAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQAREP/aAAgBAgEBPxBIDhMWL//EABsQAQEBAQADAQAAAAAAAAAAAAERACExQVGh/9oACAEBAAE/EJOCEiz7coZLp5H3dZIEeOL+ZlCEHOBh5gCKDHI4EbxO5hBSe9//2Q==&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;profile-photo&quot;
        title=&quot;profile-photo&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/db8dd83596b9c3016ab8dbe7347cb64b/828fb/potrait.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/db8dd83596b9c3016ab8dbe7347cb64b/ff44c/potrait.jpg 158w,
/static/db8dd83596b9c3016ab8dbe7347cb64b/a6688/potrait.jpg 315w,
/static/db8dd83596b9c3016ab8dbe7347cb64b/828fb/potrait.jpg 630w,
/static/db8dd83596b9c3016ab8dbe7347cb64b/0ede0/potrait.jpg 945w,
/static/db8dd83596b9c3016ab8dbe7347cb64b/3ac88/potrait.jpg 1260w,
/static/db8dd83596b9c3016ab8dbe7347cb64b/377b2/potrait.jpg 1980w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 630px) 100vw, 630px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
        decoding=&quot;async&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What did you do this past week?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past week, I managed to cook all the new recipes I learnt from my mother. Most of those are curries and frys like
tomato curry, potato curry, chicken curry, potato fry, egg fry, etc. I hope that once I get comfortable with
making these I do not have to stress about food for the rest of the semester, although they do take a bit of time to
make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other things I have been working on is practicing some coding problems with my friends and I finished
HackerRank for project Collatz!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What’s in your way?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stress of applying for internships is definetly taking its toll on me. I sit down to start working only to get hit
by the realization that I also have to apply to companies. It is hard to get anything done with that cloud hanging
over my head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What will you do next week?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start going to some org meetings that I think are cool, cook more instead of eating out, and finish all my class work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If you read it, what did you think of the Paper #2: Makefile?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The makefile looked pretty standard compared to makefiles from other projects, but having aliases for batch git
commands seems unecessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think Makefiles are in general pretty neat tools that allow you to write pipelines for compiling or testing code.
However, they do look pretty complicated to work with and require much more work to learn how to setup besides just
annotating an existing makefile. I hope we go over how a makefile works in lecture sometime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What was your experience of assertions, unit tests, and coverage? (this question will vary, week to week)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assertions&lt;/em&gt; are statements in your code that check if a boolean expression is true or not and fail immediately if false.
They make testing invariants in your algorithm easy and I use them in every project I work on. I cannot quantify how
many bugs I caught early on due to assertions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have used &lt;em&gt;Unit Testing&lt;/em&gt; before and I think it works very well for this project. The input and output are
well-defined and creating more tests is very simple. However, it does require you to know the solution ahead of time
though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have never used Coverage before and am not sure it is needed for this project. I believe it is only useful in checking
if your tests are reaching every part of your codebase. I think it is only useful for very large projects that many have
dead code that does not need to be maintained. All in all, I think this is the least useful tool of the three.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What made you happy this week?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been going to the gym with my roomates and I noticed some changes! I think my hard work is starting to pay off
now that I feel my posture and strength has improved. Here is to maintiaing my routine into the semester!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What’s your pick-of-the-week or tip-of-the-week?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember taking Operating Systems (CS439)? Remember how hard it was to fix race conditions, memory leaks, and null
pointers? Well, it could have been all avoided if you used a new programming paradigm. Introducing
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org/&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt;, a programming language that does not allow code that leads to race conditions or
dangling pointers. It separates references into mutable and immutable references so that you can only have one mutable
reference of an object at a time. This already avoids problems with multiple threads writing to a single memory.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[CS373 Fall 2021: Taraka Pranav Rayudu]]></title><description><![CDATA[Where did you grow up? I spent the first half of my life in Bangalore, India. After I turned 13, my parents decided to move to the
States…]]></description><link>https://pranavrayudu.github.io/about-me/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://pranavrayudu.github.io/about-me/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 630px; &quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/6b994e0caf29ed37195b03dfbb72fcdf/377b2/profile-photo.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 100%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAUABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFwABAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAUBBv/EABUBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAIB/9oADAMBAAIQAxAAAAG1Npz4qjFHMaVaEP/EABsQAAMBAAMBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAECAwAEERMh/9oACAEBAAEFAqMVSbU9c47WX189Xc0oxw5VQP/EABURAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABBB/9oACAEDAQE/AYQ//8QAFhEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEEEB/9oACAECAQE/AaXD/8QAHRAAAQQCAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQACEDEREiMyQf/aAAgBAQAGPwIkWhybA+QUKjLnR2X/xAAcEAADAQACAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREhEDFBcaH/2gAIAQEAAT8hU1U6E3OprcfZEYkgigD2zwMUrJuCMte0f//aAAwDAQACAAMAAAAQs9e//8QAGBEBAAMBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQAQESH/2gAIAQMBAT8QA2zYPdf/xAAXEQEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABEQAQ/9oACAECAQE/EKwcQ1Df/8QAHRABAQADAAMBAQAAAAAAAAAAAREAITFBUZEQgf/aAAgBAQABPxADZADyrM1LSi4+QOTv4BmaIvKbMJRLamn3PucZpwoXB/MmIY8O/eDGQdNfuf/Z&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;profile-photo&quot;
        title=&quot;profile-photo&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/6b994e0caf29ed37195b03dfbb72fcdf/828fb/profile-photo.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/6b994e0caf29ed37195b03dfbb72fcdf/ff44c/profile-photo.jpg 158w,
/static/6b994e0caf29ed37195b03dfbb72fcdf/a6688/profile-photo.jpg 315w,
/static/6b994e0caf29ed37195b03dfbb72fcdf/828fb/profile-photo.jpg 630w,
/static/6b994e0caf29ed37195b03dfbb72fcdf/0ede0/profile-photo.jpg 945w,
/static/6b994e0caf29ed37195b03dfbb72fcdf/3ac88/profile-photo.jpg 1260w,
/static/6b994e0caf29ed37195b03dfbb72fcdf/377b2/profile-photo.jpg 1980w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 630px) 100vw, 630px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
        decoding=&quot;async&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Where did you grow up?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the first half of my life in Bangalore, India. After I turned 13, my parents decided to move to the
States, so I moved to San Antonio, Texas where I entered middle school at 7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; grade.
Three years later, I moved to Dallas, TX where I completed high school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What high school did you attend?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent my freshman year at Ronald Reagan High School in San Antonio and sophomore through senior years at Keller High
School in Keller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What was your favorite extracurricular activity in high school?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found our newly minted Robotics club to be the best extracurricular I participated in. We had a humble
yet ambitious atmosphere as we competed among thousands (3,790, to be exact) of other teams in the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.firstinspires.org/robotics/frc&quot;&gt;FIRST Robotics competition&lt;/a&gt;. We were not allowed to work on the robot after
a certain date so every regional event started off with me uploading new, untested code into the robot followed by near
complete failure and a melt-down in the entire team. Atleast it taught me the importance of writing bulletproof code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why did you come to UT?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UT is hands-down one of the best universities for Computer Science in the United States, so that made choosing UT very
obvious from the get-go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why are you majoring in CS?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked up code when found a YouTube channel called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/shiffman&quot;&gt;The Coding Train&lt;/a&gt; where
a professor named &lt;a href=&quot;https://shiffman.net/&quot;&gt;Daniel Shiffman&lt;/a&gt; made generative art using a javascript graphics library
called &lt;a href=&quot;https://p5js.org/&quot;&gt;p5.js&lt;/a&gt;. Eventually I landed on the engineering side of CS and started practicing
problem-solving and making web apps and lo and behold… I am now a CS major.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why are you in this class?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I heard this class was a classic, must-take for a CS major at UT, so I wanted to see what it was about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What are your expectations of this class?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to become proficient at writing software in large teams and know how to use all relevant tooling for such large
teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How much Javascript/Python/SQL/Web programming do you already know?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am fairly proficient in javascript and web programming since I picked those up early in high school. I use Python for
some of my projects and I used SQL for my past internship, so I have a some exposure to all these languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How did you like the first lectures?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best parts of lecture was using the versatility of Ed Discussion to ask questions in class and using a git repo
for lecture notes. I do wish it was more fast-paced though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How did you feel about the cold calling?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am fine with it, but I need a couple of seconds before talking in front of the whole class and I am afraid of not
being able to unmute myself or having some other technical issue on the spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What made you happy this week?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought a new bike to commute to campus and it works perfectly! I have even ridden to downtown Austin with it and
it is overall a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What’s your pick-of-the-week or tip-of-the-week?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://people.csail.mit.edu/jiex/papers/robogrammar/index.html&quot;&gt;RoboGrammar&lt;/a&gt; is a 2020 MIT paper which describes a
graph-based approach to generate robot structures like body joints and links. Basically, they describe a way to
generate graphs that can be turned into robots that are optimized for smooth surfaces, stepped surfaces, etc.
It is cool because even with a few nodes, you can generate a huge variety of robots. Here is
&lt;a href=&quot;https://people.csail.mit.edu/jiex/papers/robogrammar/paper.pdf&quot;&gt;the paper&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/allanzhao/RoboGrammar/&quot;&gt;source code&lt;/a&gt; if you want to check it out.
I even a linked a quick video down below for you :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-resp-iframe-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom: 56.25%; position: relative; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.0725rem&quot; &gt; &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/rSPwOeX46UA&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; &quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>